Tania Abanina

web/UX designer

photographer

Currently: Berlin, Germany
Email: hi@taniaabanina.com

Phone number: +49 (0)15 73 689 5441

Web: taniaabanina.com

Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/taniaabanina

Мойкруг: taniaabanina.moikrug.ru

Previous background

I worked as a programmer and web designer in BTI (Biysk Technological Institute, where I also studied in my home town in Russia), where I was part of a team in charge of internal database management and website development.

I started to work as a programmer and web designer in 2006 while I was studying Quality Management in university. This education has formed my very strong human-centric vision. Since 2009 I work in a freelance mode and participate on first stages of web development: conceptualising, brand strategy, wireframing mockups, graphic/web design, design interactive prototypes, front-end coding.

Specialities

Design in the browser, responsive web design, UX/UI design, templating (PHP/Wordpress, Rails, Django, Bootstrap customization).

Technologies: HTML/HTML5, CSS/CSS3, Sass/LESS, Compass, JavaScript (jQuery), SEO.

Tools: Paper & pencil, Balsamiq Mockups, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Fireworks, Adobe InDesign, Git, Mercurial, SVN, Sublime Text 2

Experience

Freelance web designer and client-side developer

September 2009 – present

Web design, client-side development, prototyping, writing expression of requirements, user interface consulting

Photographer

August 2012 - August 2013

Airbnb

Interior photographer

Web designer

May 2005 – October 2009 (4 years 6 months)

Biysk technological institute — http://www.bti.secna.ru

Web sites design and development; database design, front-end coding; content management

Teacher

October 2008 – May 2009 (8 months)

Sunday computer school at Biysk technological institute

Teacher of course «Multimedia technology» (Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Flash, Adobe Premiere, 3ds Max) for children 11-13 years

Projects

Coach at Open TechSchool

August 2012 - present

Coach on workshops about SASS and web design at Campus Party 2012. Coach on web design, CSS related workshops

Education

Biysk technological institute (branch) Altai state technical university

2002 - 2007

Diploma specialist

Special subject: Quality management

Qualification: Engineer-manager

Keywords: Management, total quality management, system of quality management, control of quality,

education management.

Courses

Design Think, Think Design at ESDIP_Berlin with Jorge Chamorro

May -July 2014

Documentary Foundation Certificate at Raindance Berlin with Eva Stotz April 2014

Summer intensive course of illustration at British Higher School of Art and Design with Viktor Melamed, Ivan Velichko, Irina Troitskaya, Anna Zhurko July 2011

Languages

English (fluent)

Russian (native)

German (basic)